Washington Academy of Sciences 085
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Washington Academy of Sciences Collection
1897-1965
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D.C.)
085
0.5 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series. The files are arranged in alphabetical order.
Biographical / Historical
The Washington Academy of Sciences was born out of a joint commission of various scientific societies in the city of Washington, D.C. In 1897, the joint commission studied the usefulness of creating a federation of all societies; they then banded together to create an umbrella organization in order to better coordinate their efforts to maximize membership and fellowship. The original three societies were the Philosophical, the Anthropological, and the Biological Societies of Washington, D.C. One of the most notable members of the Washington Academy of Sciences was Alexander Graham Bell, inventor of the telephone. The Academy continues to exist in 2020, with nearly 60 affiliated organizations.
Custodial History
The materials in this collection were removed from the DC Public Library Special Collections Department's vertical files and the Cutter Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of by-laws, directories, journals, clippings, rules, and programs related to the Washington Academy of Sciences from 1897-1965.
Science; Societies and clubs; Organizational Records; Ephemera
- Series 1
  - Act of Incorporation By-Laws, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ballot - Amendments to the By-Laws, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1932-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Directory, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Directory, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Directory, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Directory, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Directory, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Directory, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Directory, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Directory, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Directory, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Directory, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Directory, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - History of the Joint Commission of the Scientific Societies of Washington, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences, May 1938 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences, March 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Meeting Announcements, 1940-1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Officers, 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Programs, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Rules of the Board of Managers, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)